

**** 901-289-8381 8900 Research Park Dr. Apt 702 The Woodlands, O Imomoh91/Personal-**Projects**

SKILLS

STATISTICAL ANALYSIS: Hypothesis Testing, Regression Modeling, Hyper Parameter Optimization, A/B Testing DATA SCIENCE: Tableau, Data Wrangling, Data Cleaning, SciKit, Machine Learning, Numpy,

Pandas, Data Visualization

CODING LANGUAGES: Python, SQL, Spark

SUMMARY

I am an experienced data analytics professional with a background in statistical analysis, data wrangling, and machine learning algorithms. I'm passionate about helping others understand key business opportunities through visualizations and presentations of insight through data. I often attend data science events around Houston to sharpen my skills and learn new techniques within data science.

PROJECTS

CONSUMER CLUSTERING PROJECT

In this project, I used consumer data to create an unsupervised clustering model to group consumers based on purchase history. Using python code and data visualization, I manipulated the data to find the optimum number of groups for the model to generate. I found that the model worked best when grouping consumers into 3 distinct groups. Based on those findings, individuals within those 3 groups would each receive unique marketing material based on the groups' purchases history.

HOUSING PRICE PREDICTION MODEL

In this project, I attempted to use features of a home to predict sales prices for first time home buyers. Using data available on the web, I generated a data set that included the 70+ different predictor variables and observations. The dataset included a number of variables that were either highly correlated with one another or contained missing values. Using python programming, I was able to clean the dataset leaving only observations that had full records. Next, I proceeded to identify the combination of predictor variable that best explained the variation in sales price. I was able to use the significant variable to generate a prediction model using sci-kit learn and create an in-depth report on my insights.

METACRITIC PREDICTION MODEL

In this project, I gathered information from the website 'Metacritic' to create a prediction model for future scores. Using python code, I cleaned, manipulated, and visualized the data. After some statistical analysis, I was able to identify the best features for model construction. Ultimately after some optimization, I was able to account for most of the variation between predicted and actual scores. I also wrote a detailed report of my process and recommendations on ways to increase scores.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

AON HEWITT

The Woodlands. Tx 2016 to 2017

- Develop Excel spreadsheets that automatically calculate defined retirement benefits for multiple pension plans using V-lookups, formulas, macros, etc.
- Assist with the creating, testing, and implementing customized calculation system for new clients according to the plan provisions and administrative requirements. Create monthly client reports detailing pension plan activity and funds.
- Conduct and test monthly data load to ensure data quality.
- Developed a better data testing process that eliminated errors in our monthly data load procedure by 15% Created and implemented a data mining project to classify and categorize participants within the pension database that were previously missing.
- Developed Mass lump sum solicitations to increase pension lump-sum take rate.

NORTHWESTERN MUTUAL

Fayetteville, AR 2012 to 2013

- Market financial services to 20-30 different clients weekly, to collaborate on an effective financial plan suiting individual financial goals and needs.
- Develop client reports with visualizations based on financial status and create a presentation to illustrate financial opportunities and needs based on each client's financial aoals.
- Collaborate with managers on ways to market to financial services to multiple demographic groups.

OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Professional Athlete for Athletics Federation of Nigeria

Professionally compete in various track and field events around the world for Nigeria.

2013 to 2016

- World Track and Field championship Qualifier 2013
- 2nd Fastest 800m time in the World 2013
- New balance indoor games champion in 2014

EDUCATION

Springboard

Certification Data Science 2018

University of Arkansas at Fayetteville B.S.B.A Economics 2014